Knolls Action Project; Records apap105
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Military Resistance and Nuclear Disarmament, 1965-1993; 7; 5.0 cubic ft.
  - Draft: Conscientious Objection, 1965; 1970-1971; 1980-1982; 1984-1985; 1990-1991 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 35)
    Contains letters, clippings, flyers, articles; also information pertaining to Supreme Court cases regarding military exemption. Includes Handbook for Conscientious Objectors prepared by CCCO (1981).
  - Draft: Corporate Ties, [Undated] (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 36)
  - Draft: Correspondence, 1980; 1985-1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 37)
    Correspondence regarding controversial decision by CCCO to accept free advertising in Playboy magazine. Notes from Upstate Resistance meeting (June 21, 1987) and minutes from anti-militarism gathering (April 19, 1986); minutes from Upstate Resistance Networking meeting (October 26, 1985); notes from Draft Organizers meeting (March 2, 1980).
  - Draft: Counter - Recruitment, 1979-1982; 1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 38)
    See oversize box for Citizen Soldier (1981).
  - Draft: Counter - Recruitment, 1984-1987 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 39)
    Includes notes from CCCO Basic Training for Military Counselors (Oct. 27, 1986), also information from Upstate Resistance. See oversize box for two copies of Resistance News (1986, 1987) and one copy of CCCO News Notes (1986).
  - Draft: Court Cases, 1980; 1982; 1984-1986 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 40)
    Flyers, newsletters, clippings.
  - Draft: Doctors, 1989 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 41)
    Article from Federal Register: Selective Service, "Proposed Health Care Personnel Delivery System".
  - Draft: Financial Aid, 1982-1983 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 42)
    Clippings, articles, flyers containing information on college aid and the draft registration.
    Includes article from Federal Register: Department of Education, "Student Assistance General Provisions".
  - Draft: Gays and Military, 1985 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 43)
  - Draft: General Information, 1980-1983 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 44)
    See oversize box for two handmade posters "Don't Register for WWIII: Resist the Draft".
  - Draft: Graphics, [Undated] (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 45)
    Graphics used for publications.
  - Draft: Intervention, 1983-1984 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 46)
    See oversize box for two copies of CALC Report (Clergy and Laity Concerned) (1983, 1984).
  - Draft: Iran War, 1991 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 47)
  - Draft: Larsen, Erik, Undated (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 48)
    Visit to Albany by the first member of the military to refuse to serve in the Persian Gulf.
  - Draft: Legalities, 1980; 1982 (Box 1 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 49)
    See oversize box for poster advertising "Interview a vet" contest, sponsored by CCCO.
  - Draft: Legislation and Regulations, 1980; 1982-1984 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 1)
  - Draft: Mager, Andy, 1984-1985 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 2)
    Flyers and newsletters supporting the Syracuse draft resister.
  - Draft: Medical Deferments, 1983 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 3)
  - Draft: Militarism, 1976; 1980-1982; 1984 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 4)
  - Draft: Military Counseling, 1982-1990 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 5)
    Contains primarily information for military counselors, including The Objector: Journal of Draft and Military Counseling.
  - Draft: Military Counseling, 1991-1992 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 6)
    See oversize box for three issues of The ANTI-WARrior (1991-1992); Also, a copy of StormWarning (1991) published by Vietnam Veterans Against the War Anti-Imperialist.
  - Draft: Military Counseling - Middle East, 1990-1991 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 7)
    Clippings describing the stories of resisters.
  - Draft: Military Counseling (Old training sessions), 1982; 1986; 1991 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 8)
  - Draft: Miscellaneous, 1980-1993 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 9)
    Leaflets, flyers and newsletters.
  - Draft: NISBCO (National Interreligious Service Board for Conscientious Objectors), 1991 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 10)
  - Draft: Objector:Journal of Draft and Military Counseling, 1980-1985 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 11)
  - Draft: Objector:Journal of Draft and Military Counseling, 1986-1992 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 12)
  - Draft: Organizations - Committee Against Registration and the Draft (CARD), 1980; 1984-1985; 1988 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 13)
  - Draft: Organizations - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors (CCCO), 1978-1979; 1982; 1984; 1987; 1990 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 14)
    See oversize box for poster "Standing Up for Peace" contest. Also copies of CCCO News Notes (1987-1993).
  - Draft: Organizations - General, 1979; 1983-1988 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 15)
    See oversize box for Conscience & Military Tax Campaign Newsletter (CMTC), ON GUARD (Citizen Soldier), Resistance News (National Resistance Committee), fact sheets prepared by Promoting Enduring Peace.
  - Draft: Outreach - High Schools, 1980-1981; 1986; 1991-1992 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 16)
  - Draft: Outreach - Labor, 1980; 1983 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 17)
  - Draft: Pacifism, 1979-1984 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 18)
    Contains leaflets, clippings and articles, some from religious organizations; also a copy of Neither Victims nor Executioners by Albert Camus. See oversize box for copy of The NONVIOLENT Activist (1986) and War and Peace: A Handbook for Peacemaking in Upstate New York.
  - Draft: Persian Gulf Resisters Literature, 1991 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 19)
  - Draft: ROTC, 1974; 1981; 1984 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 20)
    Includes a copy of Military Training for 14-year olds: The growth of high school ROTC, a study sponsored by the United Church Board for Homeland Ministries with the cooperation of NISBCO.
  - Draft: Racism, 1978-1979 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 21)
    Flyers, articles and clippings pertaining to African-Americans in the military. Includes congressional Black Caucus statement in opposition to the reinstitution of the draft and draft registration.
  - Draft: Registration, 1980; 1982; 1985 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 22)
  - Draft: Registration and Draft, 1983-1985 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 23)
    See oversize box for copy of Resistance News (1984).
  - Draft: Resist, 1983-1985 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 24)
  - Draft: Resistance, 1980-1984 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 25)
    Flyers, newsletters; includes Prosecution of Non-Registrants: An organizer's guide, produced by CARD, Military Law Task Force (NLG) and Washington Area Military and Draft Law Panel.
    See oversize box for five copies of Resistance News (1982, 1983,1984).
  - Draft: Resistance, 1983-1987 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 26)
    Contains info from CCCO (Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors). Also, issue of military recruiters in high schools. See oversize box for Resistance News 1987, three CCCO News Notes 1987, and The Nonviolent Activist 1987.
  - Draft: Resources List, 1982-1986; 1988-1991 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 27)
    Products and literature lists.
  - Draft: SANE, 1979-1980 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 28)
    Literature from the Washington D.C.-based organization for disarmament.
  - Draft: Spanish Language Materials, 1972; 1979 (Box 2 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 29)
    See oversize box for poster advertising the Finger Lakes Military Counseling and Information Center. Also, handmade poster advertising war resistance and draft counseling, and posters from CCCO, Veterans for Life, and NISBCO.
  - Draft: Statistics (Vietnam), [Undated] (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 1)
    Handwritten, un-cited statistics.
  - Draft: Strategies, 1980; 1982 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 2)
  - Draft: "Un - Registration", [Undated] (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 3)
    Un-Registration campaign launched by the Committee Against Registration and the Draft.
  - Draft: Upstate Resistance, 1985; 1987-1988 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 4)
    Minutes of the July 20, 1985 meeting, report prepared by Mark Chupp (November 23, 1987), notes from winter meeting (March 1, 1987).
  - Draft: Vietnam, 1982 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 5)
    Article by Vietnam Vet.
  - Draft: War Resisters League, 1979-1981; 1987 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 6)
    See oversize box for four copies of The NONVIOLENT Activist (1987, 1991).
  - Draft: Women and the Military, 1979-1982; 1990 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 7)
  - Draft: Youth, Militarism Conference, 1987-1988 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 8)
    Minutes of planning meetings for National Conference on Youth, Militarism and Alternatives, a conference to aid counter-recruitment organizers.
  - Draft:Youth and Militarism Directory - A guide to counseling help for young people, 1992-1993 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 9)
  - Economic Conversion, 1981-1989 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 10)
    Leaflets, articles, newsletters, clippings.
    Includes a special issue of WIN: Peace and freedom through nonviolent action on "Conversion Organizing". See oversize box for an issue of the Berkshire Economy (Feb.27, 1987) dealing with Industrial Crisis. and Opportunity.
  - Economic Conversion, 1985-1987 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 11)
    Includes a review of Jobs with Peace campaign economic conversion efforts (1987), reports on military spending in New York, paper by Seymour Melman "A Road Map, Not a STOP Sign: Politics of Peace".
  - Economic Conversion, 1986-1987 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 12)
    Includes report to Governor Dukakis by the Governor's Advisory Committee on the impact of the nuclear arms race on Massachusetts (1986).
  - Economic Conversion, 1986-1989 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 13)
    Includes information sent by Louise McNeilly of the Center for Economic Conversion to Carolyn Mow; also information on conversion projects in other states and Canada.
  - Economic Conversion (Publications), 1978; 1981; 1984-1985 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 14)
    Publications by the President's Economic Adjustment Committee, Department of Defense, Center for Economic Conversion.
  - Economic Conversion (Publications), 1992-1993 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 15)
    Positive Alternatives, publication of the Center for Economic Conversion.
  - Economic Conversion: CABEC Mailing List, 1986-1987 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 16)
    Capital Area and Berkshire County Economic Conversion Study Group.
  - Economic Conversion: CONDEC (Clippings), 1985; 1988 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 17)
    Clippings pertaining to closing of ConDiesel in Niskayuna in 1985.
  - Economic Conversion: Clark, Karen, 1987 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 18)
    Minnesota state legislator involved in economic conversion issues. See Series 9 for cassette tape of Seminar on Economic Conversion (January 10, 1987).
  - Economic Conversion: Economic Effects/Social Costs of Militarization, 1980-1986; 1989 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 19)
  - Economic Conversion: Examples of Conversion, 1983-1988 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 20)
  - Economic Conversion: "GE workers try to kindle new industry in old plant", [Undated] (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 21)
    Leaflet taken from article in Los Angeles Times.
  - Economic Conversion: Legislative and Executive Initiatives, 1982; 1984-1987 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 22)
  - Economic Conversion: Minnesota, 1986 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 23)
  - Economic Conversion: Plowshare Press, Center for Economic Conversion (CEC), 1986; 1988-1989 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 24)
    Conversion Briefs (CEC, 1988), bibliographies and resource listings.
  - Economic Conversion: Weapons Facilities Conversion Network, 1987-1989 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 25)
    Information prepared by this organization, minutes of meetings. Also contains "Political Strategies for the Economic Conversion of Military Production", a paper prepared by Donald Wells for delivery to the Canadian Political Science Association (1988).
  - Economic Conversion: Women, 1983; 1985-1986 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 26)
  - Economic Diversification Conference, 1989 November 18 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 27)
  - Event Flyers, [Undated] (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 28)
  - Fast for Life, 1983 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 29)
    Information pertaining to worldwide action for disarmament. See oversize box for two copies of Fast for Life newsletter.
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation (FOR), 1979; 1982; 1985-1986 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 30)
    Articles, publications.
  - Foreign Policy, 1982-1987 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 31)
    Clippings, leaflets, articles.
  - Freeze (Disarmament), 1981-1984; 1988 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 32)
  - "The Freeze Economy", 1983 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 33)
    Publication prepared by the Nuclear Weapons Freeze Campaign.
  - Guidelines for New Leafletters, 1986 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 34)
  - High Technology Professionals for Peace, 1981-1982; 1988 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 35)
    Information pertaining to and distributed by this organization.
  - Humor, 1981-1983; 1986 (Box 3 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 36)
  - Institute for Community Economics, 1984-1986 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 1)
  - Japanese Peace Movement, 1987 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 2)
  - KAP Photos, [Undated] (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 3)
    One photo of "Stop Trident" demonstration.
  - Knolls/Trident Fact Sheet, 1986 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 4)
  - Labor, 1982-1987 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 5)
    Leaflets and articles; Publications of the Labor Research Association, Industrial Union Department (AFL-CIO), Labor Education and Research Project; Labor Area Summaries published by the NYS Department of Labor. See oversize box for two copies of IUE News (1986) and one copy of The Mill Hunk Herald (1983).
  - Labor: Electric Boat (careers), [Undated] (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 6)
    Recruitment information from Electric Boat Division of General Dynamics.
  - Labor: Jobs with Peace, 1983-1985 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 7)
    Contains Jobs with Peace newsletters and literature, leaflets, and information pertaining to Peace with Justice Week. See oversize box for Jobs with Peace Campaign Report, Special Edition.
  - Labor: Jobs with Peace Week, 1983 April 10-1983 April 17 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 8)
  - Labor: Local 301, [Undated] (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 9)
    Clipping, handwritten notes on I.U.E. Local 301.
  - Labor: Worker Conscience, 1982-1988 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 10)
    Articles, clippings, leaflets; also "Are you considering a career in the defense industry?" prepared by High Technology Professionals for Peace.
  - Labor: Worker Support/Alternative Employment, 1985-1987 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 11)
    Copies of Peacework Alternatives News.
  - Labor: Worker Support - KAP, 1982-1983; 1985-1986 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 12)
    KAP Worker Support Program. Contains handwritten notes and notes from committee meetings.
  - Leaflets (Potential), 1990-1993 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 13)
  - MTRAF (Military Tax Resistance and Alternative Fund), 1980-1983; 1986 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 14)
    Contains meeting agenda, minutes and notes.
  - MTRAF: Archives, 1980-1981 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 15)
    Resource list, "Statement of Purpose" flyers, information from the Center on Law and Pacifism.
  - MTRAF: Archives, 1980-1986 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 16)
    Posters, handouts, letters.
  - MTRAF: Brochures, Mailings (originals), 1981-1986 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 17)
  - MTRAF: Mailings, Flyers, 1983-1985 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 18)
  - MTRAF: Press Releases and Newspaper Clippings, 1981-1986 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 19)
  - MTRAF: Re-Distribution, 1982-1986 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 20)
    Contains letters, thank you notes, and information regarding the program and distribution of funds.
  - MTRAF: Original Materials, 1981-1986 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 21)
    Flyers and general information sheets; also, Affirm Life: Pay for Peace, a handbook for World Peace Tax Fund Educations/Organizers (1981), People Pay for Peace: A military tax refusal guide for radical religious pacifists and people of conscience, published by Center Peace Publishers (1982), Guide to War Tax Resistance, War Resisters League (1981).
  - MTRAF: Sample letters and Statements from Contributors, 1980; 1982-1984 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 22)
  - MTRAF: Tax Resistance Counselor Training, 1983 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 23)
  - MX Missile, 1981; 1985 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 24)
  - Massachusetts Industrial Policy Group, 1987 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 25)
  - Middle East Conflict, 1980-1981; 1983-1984; 1987 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 26)
    Leaflets; also newsletter published by the American-Arab Anti-Discrimination Committee.
  - Military Leaders on Nuclear Issues, 1979; 1981-1984; 1988 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 27)
    Flyers, leaflets; also, three articles from the Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science (September 1983) opposing nuclear armament.
  - Miscellaneous Newsletters, 1991 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 28)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, Articles, 1990-1991 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 29)
    Includes article from Mother Earth News on the effects of Chernobyl on a Swedish organic farm, and correspondence regarding an appeal of the denial of a FOI request.
  - Miscellaneous Publications, 1991 (Box 4 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 30)
    Includes publications of the CEC, Institute for Community Economics, Southwest Research and Information Center, UpRiver/DownRiver, and Campaign for Peace and Democracy.
  - MOBE (Mobilization for Survival), 1984-1988 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 1)
    Information from and about MOBE. See oversize box for 10 copies of The Mobilizer (1981-1984).
  - MOBE: Conference, 1988 January (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 2)
    Includes information on MOBE programming, structure, finances, proposal for a political program. Also includes correspondence regarding KAP's changing relationship with MOBE.
  - MOBE: Speaking Tour, 1990 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 3)
  - MOBE: Weapons Facilities Network Bulletin, 1986-1988 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 4)
  - NARMIC (National Action Research on the Military Industrial Complex), 1978 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 5)
    Newsletter.
  - NARMIC: Pentagon Audit Project, 1987 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 6)
    Data printout.
  - Nuclear Accidents, 1980-1981; 1986-1987; 1989 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 7)
    Clippings, flyers, leaflets.
  - Nuclear Free Zones, 1987-1988 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 8)
  - Nuclear Issues (various statements), 1980-1990 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 9)
    Leaflets, articles, clippings.
  - Nuclear Power, 1979; 1984; 1987-1988; 1991 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 10)
    Articles, flyers, clippings.
    See oversize box for two copies of Energy News Digest.
  - "Nuclear War: What's Your Plan?", [Undated] (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 11)
    Handout prepared by the Orange County (CA) Alliance for Survival.
  - Nuclear War Effects - Nuclear Winter, 1980-1987 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 12)
    Articles, leaflets, clippings, flyers from several organizations.
  - Nuclear Weapons Facilities Networking Project - Upstate, 1982-1985 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 13)
    Contains minutes of meetings; also "Disarming your local nuclear weapons facility.A skills sharing and networking conference for organizers" (conference proceedings, 1982).
  - Nuclear Weapons Facilities Task Force, 1982 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 14)
  - Organizations - Peace and Religious, 1979-1982; 1985 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 15)
    Contains flyers and handouts. See oversize box for 2 copies of The Catholic Worker (1982).
  - Peace Organizations - New York State, 1980-1984 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 16)
    Newsletters and information from various organizations.
  - Peace Walks, 1988 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 17)
  - Persian Gulf War, 1991 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 18)
    Includes War in the Gulf: An environmental perspective, prepared by the Political Ecology Group (PEG), and Desert Folly: Background paper on the war with Iraq, by Bob Aldridge.
  - Poetry/Personal Statement, 1980-1987 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 19)
    Leaflets, articles and clippings containing poetry and personal statements.
  - Polls - Local Communities, [Undated] (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 20)
    Contains a questionnaire from the summer of 1980, cards documenting interactions during a house-to-house canvas (Undated), responses to poll of May 1, 1982, and leafleting data forms from 1985.
  - Postcards, [Undated]; photo-ready graphic (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 21)
  - Religious Groups and Issues, 1979; 1981-1985 (Box 5 (7-Military Resistance and Nuclear ), Folder 22)
    Booklets, handouts, clippings.